Guide to the Desarrolla Records, 2014-2016 UA.31.06.0002
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Desarrolla Records
2014-2016
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University -- Desarrolla
UA.31.06.0002
0.14 Gigabytes Electronic files shared via Google Drive
Desarrolla is a student organization whose goal is to promote Latin America by encouraging partnerships between members of the Duke community and communities within Latin America. The Desarrolla Records span 2014-2016 and include founding documents, organization information, records of the marketing and networking teams, and brand image materials.
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 2014, Desarrolla is a Student Organization Finance Committee-funded organization whose goal is to promote Latin America by encouraging partnerships between members of the Duke community and communities and countries within Latin America. From their website, Desarrolla promotes its goals by positioning Latin America among Duke members as a continent of opportunities and empowered communities, facilitate partnerships between Latin America and the Duke community, and support sustainable projects that empower Latin American communities and organizations.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Electronic records in this collection have been migrated to a library server and digital use copies can only be accessed onsite in the Rubenstein Library Reading Room.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Desarrolla Records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 2016.
Collection Overview
The Desarrolla Records span 2014-2016 and include founding documents, organization information, records of the marketing and networking teams, and brand image materials. Founding documents consist of iterations of the organization's constitution and by-laws. Organizational records include organizational charts, a vision and recruitment video, and a year-end presentation describing progress made. Records of the marketing and networking teams include marketing metrics, survey results, and materials used to promote the organization and its mission.
Duke University -- Students; Duke University -- Students -- Societies, etc; Latin America -- Relations -- United States
- Organizational Records, 2014-2016; 1
  - Constitution and By-Laws, 2014-2016; 11 PDF files; approximately 2 megabytes.
  - Communications, 2014-2015; 5 digital images and 3 PDF files; approximately 6 megabytes.
  - Fundraising, 2014-2015; 2 PDF files; approximately 1 megabyte.
  - Organization Information, 2014-2015; 1 digital image and 2 PDF files; approximately 1 megabyte.
  - Marketing, 2015-2016; 3 PDF files; approximately 1 megabyte.
  - Networking, 2015-2016; Document files; approximately 16 megabytes.
  - Organization Information, 2015-2016; Document files and one MP4 video file; approximately 119 megabytes.
  - Brand Image materials, 2014-2016; 5 digital images and 1 PDF; approximately 1 megabytes.
  - Desarrolla web archives, 2016